Contato

+610476252820 (Mobile) shimada@nikkei.one

www.linkedin.com/in/thiago4go (LinkedIn)

Principais competências

Docker

Communication

General Administration

Languages

Japanese (Professional Working)

Spanish (Elementary)

Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)

English (Full Professional)

Certifications

Introduction to Web Development with HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Agile Scrum Master

Japanese-Language Proficiency Test N2

Introduction to Web Accessibility WCAG 2.1

Docker Training Course for the Absolute Beginner

Honors-Awards

THIRD PRIZE WINNERS in the 28th JMEC - TEAM 5 - Cooper Surgical

Thiago Sinji Shimada Ramos

ICT Developer | Fullstack | Linux | Python | Kubernetes | Laravel | PHP | Tailwind | Ecommerce

Melbourne, Vitória, Austrália

Resumo

10+ years of total experience, with 5 years in IT industry. A seft-taught programmer with a B.B.A. degree. Delivering topquality, clean code on time and within budget, surpassing client expectations. Proficient in diverse technologies and a quick learner. Multicultural background. Build effective communication and teamwork.

Experiência

Designs To You

9 meses

Information Communication Technology Developer janeiro de 2024 - Present (3 meses)

Melbourne, Victoria, Australia

Web Developer

julho de 2023 - janeiro de 2024 (7 meses)

Melbourne, Victoria, Australia

K8SUG

Co-host (Volunteering)

julho de 2023 - Present (9 meses)

Melbourne, Victoria, Australia

K8SUG is a group for anyone interested in Kubernetes from anywhere to join online or in-person in Melbourne, Australia. We meet to talk about anything Kubernetes / OpenShift related including but not limited to how to Build, Secure, Operate, Manager Kubernetes Clusters, how to Secure and Backup containers, Migrate containers between On-Premises and across Multi-Cloud, how the DR works for the containers etc.

Nikkei One Full Stack Developer janeiro de 2023 - Present (1 ano 3 meses)

- Web Development using JavaScript and CSS to create responsive and interactive UI/UX.
- Customised modules and design changes using PHP/HTML and XML.
- Managed and optimized MySQL databases for website performance.
- Helped interdisciplinary teams meet deadlines and budgets.
- Helped a help desk solve technical issues
- Administrated the project's Git/Github repository.

株式会社エグゼクティブプロテクション Executive Protection, Inc. Security Officer

novembro de 2022 - abril de 2023 (6 meses)

Japan

- Coducted physical security of the data center and restricted areas, including metal detection and visual inspections of staff and visitors.
- Monitored and regulated access to the data center and restricted areas to ensure compliance with security policies and procedures.
- Collaborated with various departments to identify and address security flaws and make recommendations for enhancements to improve data security.

Kickante: Crowdfunding + Financiamento Coletivo Project Manager março de 2018 - maio de 2018 (3 meses)

São Paulo

Job description:

- -Create and execute a crowdfunding project
- -Promote the campaign by email and SNS
- -Negotiation with supplier
- -Development of relationships with investors

<Results>

In a short period of only 45 days, created, developed, and signed a crowdfunding project to cover the cost of representing Brazil in the World Amateur Go Championship held in Tokyo. The established goals have been achieved 100%.

Gympass

Management Information System Assistant janeiro de 2017 - fevereiro de 2018 (1 ano 2 meses)

São Paulo Area, Brazil

Job description:

- -Developed tools using Excel to support Risk management
- -Data extraction by VBA / Excel and SQL
- -Created reports to support Gym's sales team
- -Monthly reporting to country managers of integrated fraud prevention results

<Results>

At the company, my boss praised my flexible and altruistic personality and said that it helped me communicate and innovate between the sales team, system development team, and company managers. The tool I helped develop was able to detect the failure and take corrective action, avoiding the financial losses of thousands of Brazil Real. This success has allowed us to give online presentations in English to colleagues in Europe, America, and Latin America.

FIA - Fundação Instituto de Administração International MBA Monitor novembro de 2015 - abril de 2016 (6 meses) São Paulo e Região, Brasil

Job description

- -Supported administrative tasks related to research and education
- -Promotion of communication in English between international students from overseas.
- -Monitored and collected MBA class quality surveys.
- -Provided a weekly schedule by email to inform students of assignment deadlines and must-read articles.
- -Provided instructions to students to prepare documents related to public transport in São Paulo

<Results>

By monitoring my MBA classes, I gained valuable knowledge about differences in business culture. I improved my English communication skills through daily conversations with students and professors. We supported class surveys to help manage course quality and measure student satisfaction.

HSBC

Intern - Product Control maio de 2015 - novembro de 2015 (7 meses)

São Paulo e Região, Brasil

Job description:

-Search and record exchange rates of the International Monetary Fund's basket of currencies

- -Search and record of Brazilian stock market indexes and indicators
- -Attention to data details and accurate input
- -Integration of financial information of bank positions in international debt systems
- -Automated Excel sheets execution using macros
- -Supported the process of statistical analysis

<Results>

The department I worked as an intern worked after business hours by supporting the bank's financial operations, and at the end of the month, I had overtime to complete the entire process. I was just an intern, but I also worked overtime to help the team to the end. Unfortunately, at the end of the year, the banking business was sold to a Brazilian bank and I retired because my ambition to work in an international environment was not guaranteed.

ONCLICK

Enterprise Resources Planning Consultant agosto de 2010 - fevereiro de 2013 (2 anos 7 meses)

São Paulo, Brazil

Job description:

- -Supported software and database installation
- -Supported data processing and transfer from previous systems
- -Provided help desk by phone and email
- -Trained client management staff to use ERP system features
- -Verification of implementation project scope
- -Onsite customer service
- -Reported the business and status of the project

<Results>

The scope of all projects was properly validated and completed in time with few changes. Due to the involvement of multiple processes, we were able to properly understand and assist our clients over the phone or email. Therefore, I wanted to receive an education in business administration. I got a full scholarship at one of the best business schools in Brazil.

Formação acadêmica

FIA Business School

Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A.), Business Administration and Management, General · (2013 - 2018)

ETEC Getúlio Vargas

Ensino Médio e Técnico em Eletrônica · (2006 - 2008)